It is important that the steps become as high so that you do not stumble into the stairs.
I have measured the height from the floor in the machine room to the floor of the attic.
With twelve steps, the step height becomes 18.3 cm.
And that's so wide I saw the template.
Then I make a jig to get the steps just the same.
I start by attaching the template by the step height so that it has the same angle as the underside of the piece.
Then I have a piece of sacrifice and a piece of support that I attach so that it becomes a sledge that can slip on the piece.
To get the right distance, I use the circular saw plus a rubbish piece of the same thickness as the steps.
If you want the exact pass, if it is to be really neat, then pull away the double thickness of the blade.
I build a staircase for the machine hall and it becomes much easier with some play.
That's why I ignore the fin.
The depth of the saw blade I set to fifteen millimeters - one third of the thickness of the vang.
The sacrifices can be thrown away.
I am now making a beginner's miss that it takes a while for me to discover.
See if you discover it before me ...
It's now I suddenly realize my mistake.
You may have noticed it earlier.
Look here you'll see:
I have crossed what is to be cut away.
But sawn on the wrong side of the line all the time.
As you can see, the top step is a little too far, but I saw it so it fits perfectly.
As you can see, I have attached the stairs with just one screw in the side that faces from the wall.
Why should I show just soon.
To secure the stairs, I attach it with two screws on the top.
The stairs in place but not yet finished.
I will look for it by changing the screws to wooden plugs.